Hospital Graduates' Club
Hospital Graduates' Club Records
1886-1959
Hospital Graduates' Club
1 linear foot
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Note
The Hospital Graduates' Club was formed in 1886 for the purpose of "the advancement of medical science, and of the mutual interest of its members." Hospital graduates of one year were eligible for membership. Active membership was limited to 50 members, and associate membership was available for those who were restricted by time or location from participating in the New York based club. The club held monthly meetings October through June and annual dinners. Meetings were comprised of organizational business and presentations of papers and cases.
Scope and Content
Records include minutes of general meetings and the Board of Trustees, manuscript and printed copies of the constitution, printed programs and menus, memorials, correspondence, and other materials. Many of the minutes are handwritten, while those found in the "Permanent Minutes and Records" are typescript.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Hospital Graduates' Club.; Medicine -- New York (State) -- New York -- Societies, etc.
Container List
  - Minutes, 1886-1898. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1890-1900. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes and Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1899-1916 and 1900-1910. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1916-1924. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of the Board of Trustees, 1916-1936. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Permanent Minutes and Records, 1925-1938. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Permanent Minutes and Records, 1938-1946. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Permanent Minutes and Records, 1947-1959. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Documents, 1898-1902. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, undated; 1901-1905. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1906-1914. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pamphlet "Constitution and By-laws of the Hospital Graduates' Club,", undated. (Box 1)
  - Anniversary Dinner Programs and Menus, 1896-1941. (Box 1)